Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/mitalisodhi (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Product Development Product Management Artificial Intelligence

Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Punjabi (Full Professional)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

SOCGEN Scholar

Best IIMTian All Rounder

Scholarship for Excellence in Academics

Publications

Detecting Programming Language from Source Code using Bayesian Learning Techniques

Development and Simulation of Pacman Game using MultiClient Architecture via Player/Stage Tool

Mitali Sodhi

Lead Data Scientist | Al Mentor | Researcher Bengaluru

Summary

Lead Data Scientist with more than 7+ years of industry experience in building Al-powered products and adding data science capabilities to existing product suites. Have built Data Science teams from ground up in multiple startups & MNCs and led product execution. Proficient in Machine Learning, Image Processing, Computer Vision and Deep Learning. Previously:

- 1. Built Data Science team and led product development efforts as Technical Product Manager, AI & NLP at Marlabs for their flagship award-winning AI product, mAdvisor.
- 2. Headed Image Analytics division and led Data Semantics R&D efforts at DataWeave.
- 3. Designed multiple Machine Learning algorithms for touch segmentation at Samsung R&D Institute, Bangalore for their flagship Galaxy mobile devices.

Currently, building the Data Science team and leading all Data Science based efforts at HackerEarth for their talent assessment products.

Experience

HackerEarth Lead Data Scientist November 2018 - Present (1 year 10 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Building the Data Science division and leading all Al-based product development efforts at HackerEarth.

Primary responsibilities include:

- 1. Adding Data Science capabilities to HackerEarth's talent assessment products which includes building new features and improving existing offerings through Machine Learning and Deep Learning.
- 2. Hiring and retaining talents within the organization for the Data Science division.
- 3. As part of the leadership team, contributing to organization's mission and vision.

Rockstart

Al Mentor

September 2018 - December 2018 (4 months)

Mentor for Artificial Intelligence Program 2018. Helping select the top 50 applicants out of all the applications received for the Rockstart's Al Accelerator program.

https://www.rockstart.com/accelerator/artificial-intelligence/

Marlabs Inc.

Technical Product Manager - AI & NLP January 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 10 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

I work with technology team and business units for building Marlabs' flagship Al product.

Primary Responsibilities -

- 1. Managing technology team for building features based on product roadmap.
- 2. Designing product architecture and roadmaps based on business requirements.
- 3. Overseeing sprint planning and end-to-end development execution.
- 4. Building new modules and product features using Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Statistics.
- 5. Working with different business units in Marlabs for product marketing and customer engagement.

DataWeave Software Pvt. Ltd.
Senior Data Scientist
April 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 9 months)
Bengaluru Area, India

As a part of Data Semantics Team, I have worked on the following projects:

- 1. Developed algorithms for text based clustering to find similar products across thousands of e-commerce stores and millions of products with low latency. This includes classification of products based on their features and designing a normalization layer based on various text based attributes for every product.
- 2. Developed algorithms for Image based similarity mapping for products and extracting various attributes for a given product from the image. This included use of Deep Learning techniques and Image Processing algorithms.
- 3. Built APIs and micro-services for integration of back-end algorithms with front-end of core product.

Samsung R&D Institue, India Senior Software Engineer July 2014 - March 2015 (9 months) Bangalore

I was a part of the Next Gen Solutions Team of Device Solutions India Lab.

Primary Responsibilities -

- 1. To develop clustering algorithms for data captured on touch panel of mobile phones using Machine Learning.
- 2. Research on Machine Learning Algorithms for optimization of algorithms used specifically for classification and clustering of capacitance data of touch panel.
- 3. Classification of data as noise or from unintended touch.

Siemens

Research Intern

December 2013 - June 2014 (7 months)

Primary Responsibilities -

- 1. Set up of multiple node Hadoop Cluster using Hortonworks Stack.
- 2. Making the installation process Automatic using Ambari
- 3. Integrating Hadoop with CUDA using JNI
- 4. Running of MR Jobs on CUDA.

Research Designs and Standards Organization Summer Trainee June 2011 - July 2011 (2 months) Worked in Signalling Relays Lab that are used by Indian Railways on the Railway Tracks. Learnt their types, operation and the different tests performed on the relays.

Tata Motors Summer Trainee June 2010 - July 2010 (2 months)

Worked in The TCF Department of Tata Motors. The different parts of the vehicles are assembled here. Made a RF Transmitter and Receiver pair as a part of the training process.

Education

International Institute of Information Technology – Bangalore Master of Technology (M.Tech.), Information Technology · (2012 - 2014)

IIMT Engineering College
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Electronics and Communication
Engineering · (2008 - 2012)

City Montessori School, Lucknow (2002 - 2008)